# SIMON SIVA MULWA

#### P.O BOX 324 OTHAYA

Email: simonsiva13@gmail.com Phone: 0727870371 / 0737498706

#### Personal statement

I am dedicated and experienced in software developer with user support, troubleshooting, problem solving and software development. Self-directed and motivated and work effectively in a dynamic environment. Fluent in PHP, Python and SQL. Experienced in web app development, REST API development and user support. Vast knowledge of client-server applications and micro-service architecture, as well as installation and configuration of Linux web servers and docker containerization.

Portfolio: https://github.com/ssiva13 or https://ssiva13.github.io

# **Objective**

To be incorporated into a team of learners and experts to apply my skills in the software development and elevate my skill set and the current organizational level.

# **Key Skills**

## **Programming**

I am well versed in PHP, Python, HTML/CSS, and JavaScript all of which I have been initiated into at Dedan Kimathi University of Technology by my lecturers, peers, and self-practice as well. I have also gathered skills and knowledge in Python (Flask), Java Spring Boot from past work experiences and self learning. I am very skilled in Yii2, Laravel and CodeIgniter.

## Front-end Web application

I have an impressive understanding of web front-end tools and languages such React JavaScript Framework and Bootstrap stack tools.

# Containerization

I have experience working with docker containerization in configuration, development, and deployment of application images.

# **Back-end Web application and Database Management**

I am well experienced in working and developing Restful Services using different languages such as Python (Flask), PHP, JS, Java Spring Boot. I have worked with MySQL and Oracle databases.

# **Mobile Application**

I have interacted with Android studio Development Environment and developed a few applications.

# **Operating Systems**

I have a very rich understanding of both the Linux computing environment and Windows Environment.

#### **Education**

# **Kenyatta University Cisco Academy**

2018 July: CCNA 1-3

(Merit)

# **Dedan Kimathi University of Technology**

2014-2017: Bachelor's Degree in Computer Science

# Makueni Boys' High School

2010-2013: Kenya Certificate of Secondary Education

(A minus 75 points)

# PCEA Kibwezi Imani Primary School

2002-2009: Kenya Certificate of Primary Education

(A minus 391 marks out of 500)

# **Achievements and Projects**

- Online Soko app (Laravel)
- <u>Data-Request-App</u> (Yii2)
- CMS Site (WordPress CMS)

# Work experience

**KEMRI WELLCOME TRUST (March 2020 – to date) - Software Developer.** Involved in software and web development and user support. Building applications in Yii2 Framework, .NET (C#) framework, REST API Services and MySQL.

- Enables and implements software development and implementation processes through the set framework (Yii2 Framework, .NET (C#) framework).
- Collecting user system requirements for evaluation.
- Design, codes, tests, corrects, and documents programs and assists in the implementation of software which forms part of a properly engineered information or communication systems.
- Making specific determinations about system performance and ensuring that systems perform optimally.
- Responsible for analysis of current programs, diagnosis and troubleshooting of problem programs, and designing solutions to problematic programming.
- Responsible for proofing the program to develop needed changes to assure production of a quality product.
- Responsible for analysing of current programs and processes and making recommendations which yield a more cost-effective product.
- Respond to business-as-usual system requests for data and enterprise systems.
- Observe Change Control, Event, Configuration, and Incident management as minimum business processes when executing Service Design and Transition.
- Training of end users and other programme staff on the use of data applications.

# AIMSOFT LIMITED (September 2019 – March 2020) - Software Developer Associate. Involved in software and web development using Laravel Framework, Bootstrap frontend stack, JavaScript libraries and Oracle database.

 Worked with the core team that converted the aims ERP desktop app into the modern web-based system for the insurance industry.

- Customer requirement analysis and solution development for aims app features that address day to day user issues while using the aims system.
- Aims integration with other external systems with the use of APIs
- In-house software system development for AIMSOFT Ltd.

TANGAZOLETU KENYA (March 2019 – July 2019) - Agile Software Practitioner Trainee. Trained on Agile working style in the Software development world while working on different systems in the organization. Gained skills in using Jira Collaboration tool and developing in Java Spring Framework REST API services.

- Customer requirement analysis and solution development for user business-as-usual requests.
- Integration of inhouse apps with other external systems with the use of APIs
- Trained on agile methodology and tools (Jira and Confluence).

# SOFTFY SOLUTIONS (JANUARY 2018- JUNE 2018) - Software Developer Intern.

- Debugged and modified web applications
- Built and tested highly available and modular web applications in Python, HTML, JavaScript, and CSS
- Resolved computer hardware and software, printing, installation, word processing, email, and operating systems issues in office equipment

#### **Interests**

I like playing around with new technologies and learning what they do and how they behave when I am free.

I also like playing football, meeting new people, making new friends, and understanding people.

Greatest hobby is travelling to new places.